https://nycscouting.org/privacypolicy/

MenuAboutAbout GNYCAbout GNYCBoard of DirectorsStaff DirectoryPrivacy PolicyCareersReports & Publications – Tax Documents | Annual Reports | Council PoliciesNews & InfoNewsfeedScout Executives UpdatesNYC Scouter – Print NewsletterScouting Around EnewsletterShare Your Scouting NewsEmailing List RegistrationStores and Award CenterAlpine Scout Camp Trading Post – Located at the Alpine Scout CampStaten Island Scout Shop – Located at William H. Pouch Scout CampManhattan Award Center – Located in the GNYC Service CenterCouncil Service Center – Council Head QuartersProgramsCub Scouts – Youth grades K–5Scouts BSA – Youth 11–17 years oldScoutreach – Emphasized service to urban areasExploring – Co-ed 10–20 years oldVenturing – Co-ed 14–20 years oldSea Scouts – Co-ed 14–20 years oldOur Mission – The mission of the Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America is to serve society by helping to prepare young people to make ethical and moral choices over their lifetimes by instilling in them the values of the Scout Oath and Law.CouncilsBronx CouncilBronx River District
BrooklynBreukelen DistrictLenape Bay DistrictManhattanBig Apple District
QueensFounders DistrictPathfinder DistrictTomahawk District
Staten IslandAquehonga DistrictCampingCamp PropertiesAlpine Scout Camp – Alpine, NJTen Mile River Scout Camps – Narrowsburg, NYWilliam H. Pouch Scout Camp – Staten Island, NYYear Round CampingFacility RentalsConference CentersFood Service & Special EventsTenting & Lean-toFamily CampingCamping Division TeamDay CampsAlpine Day Camp – Alpine, NJ – Youth 5-12yrsPouch Day Camp – Staten Island, NY – Youth 5-12yrsBorough Day Camps – Cub ScoutsProgram OpportunitiesClimbingTeam BuildingOther ActivitiesOutdoor AdventuresTrek NYC – Come Visit NYCThe Order of the Arrow – Scoutings National Honor SocietyEagle ScoutsEagle ScoutsEagle Scouts: Eagle Scouts Project MarkersEagle Scouts: Eagle Candidate ResourcesAlumniAre you an Eagle Scout Living in New York City?Alumni NetworkHow to Get involvedResourcesGeneralResources: Additional Scouting WebsitesCampership ApplicationEagle Scouts: Eagle Candidate ResourcesResources: Publicity GuideResources: Membership ApplicationResources: Policy InformationResources: Social MediaUnit LeadersResources: For Unit LeadersPopcorn ResourcesResources: GuidesResources: Online Registration VideosResources: Online TrainingOtherJewish Committee on ScoutingNear MissIncident ReportingCalendarGive
JOIN FOR DONATION
Quis autem velum iure reprehe nderit. Lorem ipsum dolor sit nulla or narjusto laoreet onse ctetur adipisci.
Close
LOGIN FOR DONATION
Quis autem velum iure reprehe nderit. Lorem ipsum dolor sit nulla or narjusto laoreet onse ctetur adipisci.
The website is operated by the Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America with offices at 475 Riverside Drive Suite 600 New York, New York 10115.
The site editor takes your right to privacy seriously, and wants you to feel comfortable using this website. This privacy policy deals with personally-identifiable information (referred to as "data" below) that may be collected by this site. This policy does not apply to other entities that are not owned or controlled by the site editor, nor does it apply to persons that are not employees or agents of the site editor, or that are not under the site editor's control.
By visiting our website, you are accepting practice described in this privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy – Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America”). The Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time by posting such change here. Your continued use of the website after such change is made constitutes acceptance of and agreement to be bound by the terms of the Privacy Policy as modified.
The Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the following websites: www.bsa-gnyc.org, www.gnyccamps.org, www.alpinescoutcamp.org, www.camppouch.org/, www.tenmileriver.org and www.nyexploring.org. This Privacy Policy applies only to these websites. In addition to our own websites, we provide links to other third party websites that are not under the Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America’s control. The Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of any website linked to from the listed websites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our sites and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected on the sites listed.
What information does the Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America collect?
The Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America is the sole owner of the information collected on the sites. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. We may collect information from our users at several different points on our website. The personal information you provide is utilized to process and receipt your donation, to register your attendance at an event or meeting, or to respond to any of information requests you may have. All personal information provided to us is stored in databases located on servers which are behind firewalls. Donations made through our web site are encrypted using 128-bit SSL encryption. Donor anonymity will be respected. You are not required to provide any information if you do not want to. Please be aware that the user name you choose, the e-mail address you provide and any other information you enter may render you personally identifiable, and may possibly be displayed on this web site intentionally (depending on choices you make during the registration process, or depending on the way in which the site is configured) or unintentionally (subsequent to a successful act of intrusion by a third party). As on many web sites, the site editor may also automatically receive general information that is contained in server log files, such as your IP address, and cookie information. Information about how advertising may be served on this site (if it is indeed the site editor's policy to display advertising) is set forth below.
How is the information used?
Data may be used to customize and improve your user experience on this site. Efforts will be made to prevent your data being made available to third parties unless (i) provided for otherwise in this Privacy Policy; (ii) your consent is obtained, such as when you choose to opt-in or opt-out for the sharing of data; (iii) a service provided on our site requires interaction with a third party, or is provided by a third party;
(iv) pursuant to legal action or law enforcement. In the event you choose to use links displayed on this website to visit other web sites, you are advised to read the privacy policies published on those sites.
What is a cookie and does the Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America use them?
A "cookie" is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. The Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America website uses “cookies”. Upon logging into www.bsa-gnyc.org, encrypted session cookies are generated by Doubleknot, Inc. (our website provider). These cookies are used to ensure that each page that requires permissions is viewable by the party logging into the system. Also, whenever the “Remember me” box is checked upon login, a cookie is stored to ensure that the user name is retained by the web browser. These cookies do not track any personally identifiable data (i.e., credit card information, billing addresses, etc.) and does not pass any data to advertisers or any other third party. Advertisements may be displayed on this website and, if so, may set and access cookies on your computer; such cookies are subject to the privacy policy of the parties providing the advertisement. These parties usually use non-personally-identifiable or anonymous codes to obtain information about your visits to this site.
Does the Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America collect information from children?
Because we care about the safety and privacy of children online, we comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA). COPPA and its accompanying FTC regulation establish United States federal law that protects the privacy of children using the Internet. We do not knowingly collect contact or personal information from children under 13. Our Sites are not intended to solicit information of any kind from children under 13, and we have designed our Sites to block our knowing acceptance of information from children under 13 whenever age related information is requested.
It is possible that by fraud or deception by others we may receive information given to us or pertaining to children under 13. If we are notified of this, as soon as we verify the information, we will immediately obtain parental consent or otherwise delete the information from our servers. If you want to notify us of our receipt of information by children under 13, please do so by e-mailing us at webmaster@bsa-gnyc.org.
Other information regarding this Privacy Policy
Log Files
We use IP addresses to help analyze trends, administer the sites, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.
Various Registrations
In order to receive certain updates or use certain features of the sites, a user may have to first complete a re-connection form. During re-connection a user is required to give their contact information (such as name and email address). This information is used to contact the user about the services on our sites for which they have expressed interest. If asked for, it is optional for a user to provide demographic information (such as income level and gender), and unique identifiers (such as social security number), but encouraged so we can provide a more personalized experience on our sites.
Re-Connection does not constitute registration with the Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America as a member or leader. For details on how to become a registered member or leader, contact webmaster@bsa-gnyc.org.
E-Newsletter/Email List
If a user wishes to subscribe to our e-newsletter or email updates, we ask for contact information such as name, address and email address.
Online Message Boards, Chat Rooms and Social Networks
Any information you provide on the sites on message boards, chat rooms or through any social network i.e., Facebook and YouTube, that are linked through the Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America websites, whether personally identifiable or not, will be available to all visitors of those message boards, chat rooms and social networks and the Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America is not responsible.
Orders / Donations
Our sites use an order form for users to request information, products, services and to make donations. We collect visitor's contact information (like their email address) and financial information (like their account or credit card numbers if needed). Contact information from the order form is used to send information about our organization to our visitors. The visitor's contact information is also used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary and to process orders, donations, Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below.
Surveys
Our online surveys ask visitors for contact information (like their email or mailing address). We use contact data from our surveys to send the user information about Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America and its activities. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. Other data collected by online surveys is used to educate Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America about the interests and concerns of its supporters and general sites visitors concerning Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America's mission. This information is not shared with other organizations, except as set forth in the Sharing section of the policy.
Contact Lists
Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America operates email discussion, and contact lists to reach its members who request such information. Such services are run both by Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America and contracted vendors. These email addresses whether housed on Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America servers or those of our third-party contractor are not shared with any other organization, except as set forth in the Sharing section of this policy, and users may opt out of participating or receiving email information from Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America at any time. Instructions for opting out are contained within each email sent as well as on our sites help page.
Correction/Updating Personal Information
If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as your zip code), or if a user no longer desires our service, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update or remove that user's personal data provided to us. This can usually be done at the member information page or by emailing our Customer Support at webmaster@bsa-gnyc.org.
Choice/Opt-Out
Our Sites provide users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and our partners at the point where we request information about the visitor. If you wish to opt-out of receiving communications from us, please send an email to us at webmaster@bsa-gnyc.org with your complete name, address and email address.
Notification of Changes
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes here so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users through the posting of a prominent announcement of this website. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we may use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.
While this privacy policy states standards for maintenance of data, and while efforts will be made to meet the said standards, the site editor is not in a position to guarantee compliance with these standards. There may be factors beyond the site editor's control that may result in disclosure of data. Consequently, the site editor offers no warranties or representations as regards maintenance or nondisclosure of data.
How can I get more information about the Privacy Policy?
If you have questions or concerns about the Privacy Policy, you can contact the Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America web master at:
Via Regular Mail:
Greater New York Councils, Boy Scouts of America
475 Riverside Drive
Suite 600
New York, New York 10115
Via Email:
webmaster@bsa-gnyc.org
Via Fax:
1-212-633-6107
Last revised: February 8, 2016
